

NICOLE DYE

Creative Director

I am a Creative Director with 8+ years of experience in leading digital design and content teams. I have had the privilege of guiding the projects of 100+ national and local brands in countless industries to success. Some of my key achievements include:

- Increasing demand for website build services by 100% year-over-year by strategic recruitment, revamped processes, and a dedication to high-quality deliverables.
- Leading development for 40% of the top franchise recruitment websites in 2020.
- Building new revenue streams for Brand Journalists by expanding B2C website services.

CONTACT ME

- 615-578-1281
- hello@nicoledye.com
- www.nicoledye.com

WHY HIRE ME

- Designed, developed and led creative team on 100+ websites. My portfolio includes national brands such as Sonic Drive-In, Little Caesars, Wienerschnitzel, Captain D's, and D1 Training, as well as local businesses like Nashville Pedal Tavern, Just Love Coffee and Kenny Pipe.
- Produced print collateral for countless clients, including Captain D's, California Closets, Lenny's Subs, Wienerschnitzel, PostNet, Sonic Drive-In and other recognized brands.
- Guest on website design episode "How to Create a High-**Performance Franchise** Recruitment Website" on franchising podcast "What the Franchise?'
- Speaker at Just Love Coffee Conference 2018, where I unveiled the brand's new consumer-facing website.

EDUCATION

Tennessee College of Applied Technology

CAD Design

EXPERIENCE

APR 2017 - PRESENT

Brand Journalists

CREATIVE DIRECTOR

As the director of the creative team, I am charged with hiring talent, developing processes, leading strategy, supervising projects, managing deadlines, and mobilizing a team of designers, developers, videographers, and writers to deliver client success.

- Led design and development of 40% of the top 50 best franchise recruitment websites as ranked by 1851 Franchise.
- Direct cross-departmental brainstorming meetings and creative sessions that encourage collaboration and result in unified marketing campaigns across all channels.
- Manage client relationships from onboarding to delivery, ensuring effective and continuous communication through regular check-ins and bi-weekly updates.
- Inspire and mentor team through bi-weekly one-on-ones, project reviews, and cross-training.
- Work with fellow leaders in management to develop annual goals for the creative team and craft a roadmap for successfully hitting KPIs.
- Contribute to production needs, from design to development to copy, to keep projects moving forward and on target.

OCT 2016 - APR 2017 Brand Journalists

GRAPHIC DESIGNER & UX DEVELOPER

Developed eye-catching client creative, including website design, infographics, print ads, email templates, and ad creatives to increase MQLs in lead generation campaigns.

- Consistently recognized as a top-performing employee by the CEO.
- Increased demand for web design and development projects 100% year-over-year by elevating the quality of work and client satisfaction.
- Repeatedly "wowed" clients by delivering exceptional franchise websites, leading clients to retain our website design services for all departments and sister brands—resulting in a new agency revenue
- Worked with national brands, such as Sonic Drive-In, Little Caesars, Wienerschnitzel, Captain D's, and D1 Training.

CONTACT ME

615-578-1281

hello@nicoledye.com

www.nicoledye.com

DESIGN TOOLS

















DIFFERENTIATORS

- 8+ years agency experience
- Strong understanding of digital design / UX / UI
- Robust portfolio including previous work for national brands
- Deep development knowledge
- Fierce type skills
- High standards for anything that is design
- Excellent leadership and collaboration skills
- Kick-ass problem solver
- Time-conscious and able to work efficiently with others
- Energetic and passionate
- Bilingual (English & Spanish)

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

AUG 2014 - OCT 2016 Horton Group

UX DEVELOPER

Managed all phases of website projects, including project management, development, responsive design, SEO, testing, and quality assurance. Created and designed various materials for print and digital collateral.

- Designed user interfaces for eCommerce, membership, and brochure sites for national and local clients, including Kenny Pipe, Three Dog Bakery, and Pedal Tavern.
- Collaborated with content and marketing on a new billboard design for a retail client that led to an increase in sales for the client's business.
- Mentored and cross-trained junior developers and designers.

JAN 2014 - JUN 2014

Navigation Advertising

GRAPHIC AND WEB DESIGNER

Worked with a team of designers and developers to produce design collateral for a diverse set of clients.

- Prototyped design comps for Dodge, Monster, and Redbull sponsorships.
- Retouched and edited images for Rutherford's Best Doctors.
- Designed email templates, logos, and social media ads.
- Created political campaign design assets for local election candidates.

OCT 2013 - PRESENT

Freelance

UX/UI DESIGNER

Assist local businesses and franchise owners with their creative needs, including design consultation, website design and development, print ad design, and other digital design projects.

- Designed magazine ads and postcards for California Closets.
- Built websites for local startups and business professionals.
- Directed photoshoot for Rutherford County Board of Education's Special Education prom.

Let's work together! You can reach me at hello@nicoledye.com or call 615-578-1281